In the last video we defined internal energy as literally
عرفنا في الفيديو الطاقة الداخلية كحرفيا
all the energy that's in a system.
كل الطاقة التي في النظام .
That's kind of the most inclusive version,
هذا نوع من اكثر نسخة شاملة
at least in my head.
على الاقل في راسي .
So that's my system, it's some type of container.
لذا هذا النظام , انها بعض انواع الحاوية
And I have a bunch of particles in here.
ولدي مجموعة من الجسيمات في هنا .
It's literally the sum of the kinetic energies
انها حرفيا مجموع وطاقة حركية
of all these particles.
كل هذه الجسيمات .
If they had potential energies, we'd
اذا كان لديهم القدرة ونحن طاقات
throw that in there.
رمي ذلك هناك .
If they have electrical potential, we'd
اذا كان لديهم الكهربائية يمكننا
throw that in there.
رمي ذلك هناك .
If they have bonds with each other, the energies in that
اذا كان لديهم مع بعض الروابط طاقات الاخرى في ذلك
bond, we would throw it in there.
بوند , نحن نرمي انها هناك .
It's everything.
انه كل شيء .
It's all inclusive.
انها كل شاملة .
And, I told you in the last video it's unintuitive that U
واخبرتكم في اخر انها الاكثر U الفيديو
stands for internal energy.
لالطاقة الداخلية .
But I kind of think that, you know, U, it contains the
ولكن اعتقد ان ذلك تعلمون , على U ,
universe of energy.
الكون من الطاقة .
You know, that's just for me to memorize it.
تعلمون , انه فقط ل ان يحفظه .
Don't think too deeply into what I just said.
لا اعتقد ايضا ب ما قلته .
But this is internal energy.
ولكن هذا هو الطاقة الداخلية .
If you show me a system, it has some internal energy.
اذا فهذا النظام , لديها بعض الطاقة الداخلية .
It's a function of its state.
انها وظيفة من حالته .
I don't care how it got to that state, but if you told me
لا يهمني كيف وصلت الى ذلك ولكن اذا اخبرت ني
a system at a certain state, maybe with a certain pressure,
نظام , في حالة معين ربما بضغط معين
or a certain volume, or at a certain temperature-- although
او , او في حجم معينة على الرغم من ان temperature-- معينة
if you give me pressure and volume that should be enough--
اذا اعطيت ني الضغط و انه يجب ان يكون حجم enough--
I can tell you what its internal energy is.
يمكن ني ان اخبركم عنه الطاقة الداخلية .
Especially if you tell me the type of molecule I have, and
خصوصا اذا كنت تخبرني لدي نوع من الجزيئات , و
things like that.
اشياء من هذا القبيل .
Now we also said in the last video that because internal
نحن الان في اخر قال ايضا لان الداخلية الفيديو
energy is all the energy in the system, it can't be
كل الطاقة في الطاقة النظام , لا يمكن ان يكون
randomly created or destroyed.
او دمرتها عشوائيا .
It can just be transformed from one form to another.
انها يمكن ان يتحول الشكل من واحد الى اخر .
So if I have a change in internal energy, it can only
واذا كان لدي تغيير في فقط , يمكن ان الطاقة الداخلية
be due to-- well, it can be due to more than what I'm
تكون نتيجة to-- حسنا , يمكن ان تكون نظرا لاكثر من ما انا
describing.
وصف .
But in our simple world where all of the energy in a
ولكن في العالم حيث بسيطة في كل من الطاقة
system-- and maybe we're dealing with gases, because
وربما نتعامل system-- بسبب الغازات ,
that's normally what you deal with in a first-year chemistry
هذا هو عادة ما التعامل في السنة الاولي من الكيمياء
course-- it's going to be the heat that could be added to
course-- سيكون اضافة الى ذلك الحرارة
the system, plus the work done on the system.
النظام , اضافة الى العمل في النظام .
And like I said in the last video, sometimes they'll say,
وكما قلت في اخر الفيديو , احيانا يقولون ,
instead of plus the work done on the system, sometimes
بدلا من القيام بالعمل في النظام , احيانا
they'll say, minus the work that the system does.
سيقولون , ناقص العمل هذا النظام .